<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="firstTransform.xslt"?>

<mainHobbySite>
    <links>
        <link source="index.html">My Hobby</link>
        <link source="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glossary_of_basketball_terms">Terminology</link>
        <link source="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_players_in_the_Naismith_Memorial_Basketball_Hall_of_Fame">Sport Icons</link>
        <link source="contact.html">Contact Me!</link>
    </links>

    <mainContent>
        <facts about="myHobby">
            <heading>Basketball</heading>
            <bBallStory>
                Basketball began with its invention in 1891 in Springfield,
                Massachusetts, by Canadian physical education instructor James Naismith
                as a less injury-prone sport than football. Naismith was a 31-year-old
                graduate student when he created the indoor sport to keep athletes indoors
                during the winters. The game became established fairly quickly and grew very
                popular as the 20th century progressed, first in America and then in other
                parts of the world. After basketball became established in American colleges,
                the professional game followed. The American National Basketball Association (NBA),
                established in 1946, grew to a multibillion-dollar enterprise by the end of the century,
                and basketball became an integral part of American culture.
            </bBallStory>
            <pictures>
                <picture id="nba" format="png" source="images/logo.png">nba</picture>
                <picture id="ball" format="png" source="images/ball.png">ball</picture>
                <picture id="hoop" format="png" source="images/hoop.png">hoop</picture>
            </pictures>
        </facts>
    </mainContent>

    <players>
        <player id="p1" name="Kareem" surname="Abdul-Jabaar">
            <name>Kareem Abdul-Jabaar</name>
            <story>Kareem Abdul-Jabbar (born Ferdinand Lewis Alcindor Jr.; April 16, 1947) is an American former
                professional basketball player who played 20 seasons in the National Basketball Association (NBA)
                for the Milwaukee Bucks and the Los Angeles Lakers. During his career as a center,
                Abdul-Jabbar was a record six-time NBA Most Valuable Player (MVP), a record 19-time NBA All-Star,
                a 15-time All-NBA Team member, and an 11-time NBA All-Defensive Team member. He was a member of
                six NBA championship teams as a player and two more as an assistant coach, and was twice voted NBA
                Finals MVP. He was named to three NBA anniversary teams (35th, 50th, and 75th). Widely regarded
                as one of the greatest players of all time, he was called the greatest basketball player
                of all time by Pat Riley, Isiah Thomas, and Julius Erving.
            </story>
            <picture id="kareem" format="png" source="images/kareem.png">Kareem Abdul-Jabaar</picture>
            <link source="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kareem_Abdul-Jabbar">Learn More!</link>
        </player>

        <player id="p2" name="Hakeem" surname="Olajuwon">
            <name>Hakeem Olajuwon</name>
            <story>Hakeem Abdul Olajuwon (born January 21, 1963), nicknamed "the Dream", is a Nigerian-American former
                professional basketball player. From 1984 to 2002, he played center in the
                National Basketball Association (NBA) for the Houston Rockets and, in his last season,
                the Toronto Raptors. He led the Rockets to back-to-back NBA championships in 1994 and 1995.
                Olajuwon was inducted into the Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame in 2008 and the
                FIBA Hall of Fame in 2016. He is widely considered to be one of the greatest centers, as well as
                one of the greatest basketball players of all time.
            </story>
            <picture id="hakeem" format="png" source="images/hakeem.png">Hakeem Olajuwon</picture>
            <link source="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hakeem_Olajuwon">Learn More!</link>
        </player>

        <player id="p3" name="Larry" surname="Bird">
            <name>Larry Bird</name>
            <story>Larry Joe Bird (born December 7, 1956) is a former American professional basketball player, coach,
                and executive in the National Basketball Association (NBA). Nicknamed "the Hick from French Lick" and
                "Larry Legend", Bird is widely regarded as one of the greatest basketball players of all time.
                Bird entered the NBA for the 1979–1980 season, where he made an immediate impact, starting
                at power forward and leading the Celtics to a 32-win improvement over the previous season before
                being eliminated from the playoffs in the Conference Finals. He played for the Celtics during his
                entire professional career (13 seasons),
                leading them to five NBA finals appearances and three NBA championships.
                He played most of his career with forward Kevin McHale and center Robert Parish,
                considered by some to be the greatest front court in NBA history.
                Bird was a 12-time NBA All-Star, won two NBA Finals MVP awards and received the
                NBA Most Valuable Player Award three consecutive times (1984–1986), making him the
                only forward in league history to do so. Bird was also a member of the gold medal-winning
                1992 United States men's Olympic basketball team known as "The Dream Team".

            </story>
            <picture id="larry" format="png" source="images/bird.png">Larry Bird</picture>
            <link source="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Larry_Bird">Learn More!</link>
        </player>

        <player id="p4" name="Micheal" surname="Jordan">
            <name>Micheal Jordan</name>
            <story>Michael Jeffrey Jordan (born February 17, 1963), also known by his initials MJ, is an
                American businessman and former professional basketball player. His biography on the official NBA
                website states: "By acclamation, Michael Jordan is the greatest basketball player of all time."
                He played fifteen seasons in the National Basketball Association (NBA), winning six NBA championships
                with the Chicago Bulls. Jordan is the principal owner and chairman of the Charlotte Hornets of the
                NBA and of 23XI Racing in the NASCAR Cup Series. He was integral in popularizing the NBA around the
                world in the 1980s and 1990s, becoming a global cultural icon in the process.
                Jordan joined the Bulls in 1984 as the third overall draft pick,
                and quickly emerged as a league star, entertaining crowds with his prolific scoring
                while gaining a reputation as one of the game's best defensive players. His leaping ability,
                demonstrated by performing slam dunks from the free-throw line in Slam Dunk Contests,
                earned him the nicknames "Air Jordan" and "His Airness". Jordan won his first NBA title
                with the Bulls in 1991, and followed that achievement with titles in 1992 and 1993,
                securing a three-peat. Jordan abruptly retired from basketball before the 1993–94 NBA season to play
                Minor League Baseball but returned to the Bulls in March 1995 and led them
                to three more championships in 1996, 1997, and 1998, as well as a then-record 72 regular season
                wins in the 1995–96 NBA season. He retired for the second time in January 1999 but returned
                for two more NBA seasons from 2001 to 2003 as a member of the Washington Wizards. During
                the course of his professional career he was also selected to play for the United States national team,
                winning four gold medals (at the 1983 Pan American Games, 1984 Summer Olympics,
                1992 Tournament of the Americas and 1992 Summer Olympics), while also being undefeated.
                Jordan's individual accolades and accomplishments include six NBA Finals Most Valuable Player (MVP)
                awards, ten NBA scoring titles (both all-time records), five NBA MVP awards, ten All-NBA First Team
                designations, nine All-Defensive First Team honors, fourteen NBA All-Star Game selections, three
                NBA All-Star Game MVP awards, three NBA steals titles, and the 1988
                NBA Defensive Player of the Year Award. He holds the NBA records for career regular season
                scoring average (30.12 points per game) and career playoff scoring average (33.45 points per game).
                In 1999, he was named the 20th century's greatest North American athlete by ESPN, and was second to
                Babe Ruth on the Associated Press' list of athletes of the century. Jordan was twice inducted into
                the Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame, once in 2009 for his individual career, and again
                in 2010 as part of the 1992 United States men's Olympic basketball team ("The Dream Team").
                He became a member of the United States Olympic Hall of Fame in 2009, a member of the
                North Carolina Sports Hall of Fame in 2010, and an individual member of the
                FIBA Hall of Fame in 2015 and a "Dream Team" member in 2017. In 2021,
                Jordan was named to the NBA 75th Anniversary Team.
            </story>
            <picture id="micheal" format="png" source="images/jordan.png">Micheal Jordan</picture>
            <link source="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Jordan">Learn More!</link>
        </player>

        <player id="p5" name="Vince" surname="Carter">
            <name>Vince Carter</name>
            <story>Vincent Lamar Carter Jr. (born January 26, 1977) is an American former professional basketball
                player who serves as a basketball analyst for ESPN. He primarily played the shooting guard and small
                forward positions, but occasionally played power forward later in his NBA career. He was an
                eight-time All-Star and a two-time All-NBA Team selection. He is the only player in NBA history
                to play as many as 22 seasons and in four different decades, from his debut in 1999 to his retirement
                in 2020. He was the scoring leader on the 2000 United States Men’s
                Olympic Basketball Team where the USA defeated France to win the nation’s twelfth
                Men’s Basketball Olympic gold medal. He entertained crowds with his leaping ability and slam dunks,
                earning him nicknames such as "Vinsanity", "Air Canada", and "Half Man, Half Amazing".
                He has been ranked as the greatest dunker of all time by numerous players, journalists,
                and by the National Basketball Association (NBA). In addition to his dunking prowess,
                he was a prolific three-point shooter, making the sixth most three-point
                field goals in league history.
            </story>
            <picture id="vince" format="png" source="images/carter.png">Vince Carter</picture>
            <link source="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vince_Carter">Learn More!</link>
        </player>

        <player id="p6" name="Shaquille" surname="O'Neal">
            <name>Shaquille O’Neal</name>
            <story>Shaquille Rashaun O'Neal (born March 6, 1972), known commonly as "Shaq" , is an American former
                professional basketball player who is a sports analyst on the television program Inside the NBA.
                O'Neal is regarded as one of the greatest basketball players and centers of all time.
                He is a 7-foot-1-inch (2.16m) and 325-pound (147kg) center who played for six teams over
                his 19-year career in the National Basketball Association (NBA) and is a four-time NBA champion.
                After playing college basketball for the LSU Tigers, O'Neal was drafted by the Orlando Magic with
                the first overall pick in the 1992 NBA draft. He quickly became one of the best centers in the league,
                winning Rookie of the Year in 1992–93 and leading his team to the 1995 NBA Finals. After four years
                with the Magic, O'Neal signed as a free agent with the Los Angeles Lakers.
                They won three consecutive championships in 2000, 2001, and 2002. Amid tension between
                O'Neal and Kobe Bryant, O'Neal was traded to the Miami Heat in 2004, and his fourth
                NBA championship followed in 2006. Midway through the 2007–2008 season he was traded to the
                Phoenix Suns. After a season-and-a-half with the Suns, O'Neal was traded to the Cleveland Cavaliers
                in the 2009–10 season.
                O'Neal played for the Boston Celtics in the 2010–11 season before retiring.

            </story>
            <picture id="shaq" format="png" source="images/shaq.png">Shaquille O’Neal</picture>
            <link source="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shaquille_O%27Neal">Learn More!</link>
        </player>

        <player id="p7" name="Kobe" surname="Bryant">
            <name>Kobe Bryant</name>
            <story>Kobe Bean Bryant ( August 23, 1978 – January 26, 2020) was an
                American professional basketball player. A shooting guard, he spent his entire 20-year career with the
                Los Angeles Lakers in the National Basketball Association (NBA).
                Widely regarded as one of the greatest basketball players of all time, Bryant won
                five NBA championships, was an 18-time All-Star, a 15-time member of the All-NBA Team,
                a 12-time member of the All-Defensive Team, the 2008 NBA Most Valuable Player (MVP),
                and a two-time NBA Finals MVP. Bryant also led the NBA in scoring twice, and ranks fourth in
                league all-time regular season and postseason scoring. He was posthumously
                voted into the Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame in 2020 and named to the NBA 75th Anniversary
                Team in 2021.
                Bryant declared for the 1996 NBA draft and was selected by the Charlotte Hornets
                with the 13th overall pick; he was then traded to the Lakers.
                As a rookie, Bryant earned a reputation as a high-flyer by winning the 1997 Slam Dunk Contest,
                and was named an All-Star by his second season. Despite a feud with teammate Shaquille O'Neal,
                the pair led the Lakers to three consecutive NBA championships from 2000 to 2002.
                Criminal charges were later dropped after the accuser failed to testify, and a lawsuit was
                settled out of court, with Bryant issuing a public apology and admitting to a sexual encounter
                he maintained was consensual. The accusation briefly tarnished Bryant's reputation,
                resulting in the loss of several of his endorsement contracts.
                After the Lakers lost the 2004 NBA Finals, O'Neal was traded and Bryant became the cornerstone
                of the franchise. He led the NBA in scoring in the 2005–06 and 2006–07 seasons and was named
                league MVP in 2008. On January 22, 2006, he scored a career-high 81 points;
                the second most points scored in a single NBA game, behind Wilt Chamberlain's 100-point game.
                Bryant led the team to consecutive championships in 2009 and 2010,
                both times being named NBA Finals MVP. He continued to be among the top players in the league
                through the 2012–13 season, when he suffered a torn achilles tendon at age 34. His next
                two seasons were cut short by injuries to his knee and shoulder, respectively.
                Citing physical decline, Bryant retired after the 2015–16 season. In 2017,
                the Lakers retired both his Nos. 8 and 24, making him the only player in NBA history
                to have multiple numbers retired by the same franchise.
                The all-time leading scorer in Lakers history, Bryant was the first guard in NBA history
                to play 20 seasons. His 18 All-Star designations are the second most all time, and he has the most
                consecutive appearances as a starter. Bryant's four NBA All-Star Game MVP Awards are tied with
                Bob Pettit for the most in NBA history. He gave himself the nickname "Black Mamba" in the mid-2000s,
                and the epithet became widely adopted by the public.
                He won gold medals on the 2008 and 2012 U.S. Olympic teams. In 2018,
                he won the Academy Award for Best Animated Short Film for the film Dear Basketball (2017).
                Bryant died, along with his daughter Gianna and seven others, in a helicopter crash in Calabasas,
                California, in 2020. A number of tributes and memorials were subsequently issued,
                including renaming the All-Star MVP Award in his honor.
            </story>
            <picture id="kobe" format="png" source="images/kobe.png">Kobe Bryant</picture>
            <link source="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kobe_Bryant">Learn More!</link>
        </player>

        <player id="p8" name="Marcin" surname="Gortat">
            <name>Marcin Gortat</name>
            <story>Marcin Janusz Gortat (born February 17, 1984)
                is a Polish former professional basketball player. The 6ft 11in (2.11m), 240 pounds
                (110kg) center is the son of boxer Janusz Gortat. He was drafted in the second round by the
                Phoenix Suns in the 2005 NBA draft and played for the Orlando Magic, Phoenix Suns, Washington Wizards,
                and Los Angeles Clippers. He retired from professional basketball in 2020.
            </story>
            <picture id="marcin" format="png" source="images/gortat.png">Marcin Gortat</picture>
            <link source="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marcin_Gortat">Learn More!</link>
        </player>
        <player id="p9" name="LeBron" surname="James">
            <name>LeBron James</name>
            <story>LeBron Raymone James Sr. ( born December 30, 1984) is an American professional
                basketball player for the Los Angeles Lakers of the National Basketball Association (NBA).
                Nicknamed "King James", he is widely considered one of the greatest players ever and is often
                compared to Michael Jordan in debates over the greatest basketball player of all time.
                James has won four NBA championships, four NBA MVP awards, four NBA Finals MVP awards,
                three All-Star MVP awards, and two Olympic gold medals. James has scored the most points in the
                playoffs, the most career points (playoffs and regular seasons combined), and
                the second most regular seasons points, and has the seventh most career assists.
                He has been selected an NBA All-Star 18 times, to the All-NBA Team a record 18 times,
                and to the NBA All-Defensive First Team five times. He has competed in ten NBA Finals,
                the third most all time, including eight consecutively between 2011 and 2018. In 2021,
                James was selected to the NBA 75th Anniversary Team, and in 2022 became the first and only
                player in NBA history to accumulate over 10,000 career points, rebounds, and assists.
                James won his first two NBA championships while playing for the Heat in 2012 and 2013;
                in both of these years, he also earned the league's MVP and Finals MVP awards.
                After his fourth season with the Heat in 2014, James opted out of his contract to re-sign
                with the Cavaliers. In 2016, he led the Cavaliers to victory over the
                Golden State Warriors in the Finals by coming back from a 3–1 deficit,
                delivering the team's first championship and ending the Cleveland sports curse.
                In 2018, James exercised his contract option to leave the Cavaliers and signed with the
                Lakers, where he won the 2020 NBA championship and his fourth Finals MVP.
                James is also the first player in NBA history to accumulate $1billion in earnings as an
                active player.
            </story>
            <picture id="lebron" format="png" source="images/james.png">LeBron James</picture>
            <link source="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LeBron_James">Learn More!</link>
        </player>
    </players>

    <rules>
        <rule about="description">
            The rules of basketball can vary slightly depending on the level of play
            (for example professional rules differ from college rules) or where the game is played
            (international rules are different from USA's professional rules).
            These rule differences, however, are usually just variations on the basic game of basketball and the
            majority
            of the rules discussed below can be applied to almost any game of basketball played.
            The winner of a basketball game is the team with the most points.
            You get points by throwing the basketball through the opponent's hoop or basket.
            In regular play a basket made from within the three point line is worth 2 points and a basket
            shot from outside the three point line is worth three points. When shooting a free throw,
            each free throw is worth 1 point.
        </rule>
        <rule about="offence">
            Rules for the offense
            The basketball team on offense is the team with the basketball.
            When a player has the basketball there are certain rules they must follow:
            1) The player must bounce, or dribble, the ball with one hand while moving both feet.
            If, at any time, both hands touch the ball or the player stops dribbling,
            the player must only move one foot. The foot that is stationary is called the pivot foot.
            2) The basketball player can only take one turn at dribbling.
            In other words, once a player has stopped dribbling they cannot start another dribble.
            A player who starts dribbling again is called for a double-dribbling violation and looses
            the basketball to the other team. A player can only start another dribble after another player
            from either team touches or gains control of the basketball. This is usually after a shot or pass.
            3) The ball must stay in bounds. If the offensive team looses the ball out of bounds the other team
            gets control of the basketball
            4) The players hand must be on top of the ball while dribbling. If they touch the bottom of the
            basketball while dribbling and continue to dribble this is called carrying the ball and the player will
            lose the ball to the other team.
            5) Once the offensive team crosses half court, they may not go back into the backcourt.
            This is called a backcourt violation. If the defensive team knocks the ball into the backcourt,
            then the offensive team can recover the ball legally.
        </rule>
        <rule about="defence">
            Defensive Rules
            The team on defense is the team without the basketball.
            1) The main rule for the defensive player is not to foul.
            A foul is described as gaining an unfair advantage through physical contact.
            There is some interpretation that has to be made by the referee, but, in general,
            the defensive player may not touch the offensive player in a way that causes the offensive player to
            lose the ball or miss a shot.
            Rules for everyone
            1) Although the foul rule is described above as a defensive rule, it applies exactly
            the same to all players on the court including offensive players.
            2) Basketball players cannot kick the ball or hit it with their fist.
            3) No player can touch the basketball while it is traveling downward towards the basket or
            if it is on the rim. This is called goaltending. (touching the ball on the rim is legal in some games).
            Every player on the court is subject to the same rules regardless of the position they play.
            The positions in basketball are just for team basketball strategy and there are no positions in the rules.
        </rule>
    </rules>

    <contact>
        <heading>GLOBAL
            Contact Us
        </heading>
        <content>
            <appeal>If you would like to join our basketball community, find a crew to play,
                watch games or just discuss basketball related topics, don't be afraid!
                Fill the form, and we will reach out to you! There are no requirements to join,
                other than love for basketball and your will to meet new people.
            </appeal>
            <questions>
                <question placeholder="First Name" type="text" required="yes">Your First Name</question>
                <question placeholder="Last Name" type="text" required="yes">Your Surname</question>
                <question placeholder="Phone Number" type="number" required="yes">Your Phone number</question>
            </questions>
        </content>
    </contact>

    <groundBar>
        <barText>Are you lost Get back</barText>
        <link source="#">!UP!</link>
    </groundBar>

</mainHobbySite>